A few quick final points to keep in mind about the standard deviation.
هناك بضعة نقاط أخيرة سريعة يجب أن نأخذها باعتبارنا فيما يتعلق بالانحراف المعياري.
First, the standard deviation is frequently used to compare
أولًا، يُستخدم الانحراف المعياري كثيرًا للمقارنة
the spread of different groups to determine which is more spread out.
بين المجموعات المختلفة في انتشارها بغرض تحديد أيّها أكثر انتشارًا.
Second, when data pertains to money or the economy,
ثانيًا، حين تتعلق البيانات بالمال أو الاقتصاد
having higher standard deviation is associated with having higher risk.
فإن ارتفاع انحرافها المعياري يرتبط بارتفاع معدل الخطر بها.
In comparing stock prices,
عند المقارنة بين أسعار الأوراق المالية،
a stock price that changes with higher standard deviation over time is considered more
فإن سعر الأوراق المالية الذي يتغير مع ارتفاع انحرافه المعياري بمرور الوقت يُعتبر
risky than a stock price that fluctuates with lower standard deviation.
أكثر خطورة من سعر الأوراق المالية المتذبذب مع انخفاض انحرافه المعياري.
Third, for a comparison to be fair,
ثالثًا، لكي نجعل المقارنة منصفة
all data must be in the same units.
فلا بد أن تكون جميع البيانات في نفس الوحدات.
If you're measuring in dollars for one data set,
إذا كنتم تقيسون مجموعة واحدة من البيانات بمعيار الدولار،
but euros for another,
وتقيسون مجموعة اخرى بمعيار اليورو،
it's not fair to compare these data sets to determine which has the greatest spread.
فلن تكون المقارنة منصفة بين مجموعات البيانات هذه لتحديد أيّها ذات انتشار أعظم.
Finally, the variance has squared units of your original measurements.
أخيرًا، للمتفاوت وحدات تربيعية لقياساتكم الأصلية.
For example, if you were measuring revenue in dollars,
مثلًا إذا كنتم تقيسون الإيرادات بعملة الدولار
the variance has units of dollars squared,
فسيكون للمتفاوت وحدات تربيعية من الدولارات،
which isn't particularly useful.
وهي ليست مفيدة بشكل خاص.
For this reason, the standard deviation,
لهذا السبب فإن الانحراف المعياري،
which is the square root of the variance,
الذي هو الجذر التربيعي للمتفاوت،
is often deemed a more useful measurement of
عادةً ما يُعتبر قياسًا للانتشار أكثر فائدة
spread as it shares the units of the original data set.
حيث يشارك وحدات المجموعة الأصلية للبيانات؛
If you measure revenue in dollars,
وبالتالي إذا قِستم الإيرادات بعملة الدولار
the standard deviation also has units of dollars.
فسيكون للانحراف المعياري وحدات بالدولارات أيضًا.